clearlycontacts.ca 2019-05-17

# Privacy Policy - Clearly.ca

This Privacy Notice is to inform you of what personal data we, Clearly/Coastal, collect from you when you visit our website or use our services. This document will further explain why we collect it, and what we do with it. Your personal data refers to any information relating to you, specifically with regard to your name and contact details including your home address, telephone number, and email address.

Please take the time to read this Privacy Notice carefully. It is very important that you fully understand how we are processing your personal data, and how we are protecting that privacy. If you have any questions regarding our use of your personal data, please contact us with either of the email addresses listed below:

**General privacy and compliance:** Privacy@Clearly.ca 

**Data Protection Officer, Sunny Dhillon:** SunnyD@Clearly.ca

**Data we collect when you visit our website**

When you access to our website, we automatically collect and store some of your data in our server logs and in cookies, which are small text files that a web server stores in browser software. A browser sends cookies to a server when the browser makes a connection to the server

This data does not allow us to directly identify you, but it does record data related to your browsing history on our website. This includes the pages you accessed; the date and time of your request and referral URL; the date and time at which you accessed them; your search queries within the site; and information about the device you used such as its hardware model, operation system version, unique device identifier, Internet protocol address, hardware settings, browser type, and browser language.

You are not required to provide your data if you only want to visit our website. You may refuse to accept cookies by configuring your web browser accordingly (for more information, refer to the ‘help’ section of your web browser). That said, refusing cookies is likely to disrupt your navigation on our website, and may prevent you from accessing certain pages or services. 

**Data we collect when you sign up or when you order products**

Some of the services offered on our website require you to register and/or sign up with us. If you want to use these services, we will ask you to provide us with complete and accurate personal data, and also inform us if when your data needs to be updated. If you do not provide us with complete and accurate data, or if you do not inform us that your data needs to be updated, we may not be able to provide you with the services you requested.

We collect the following categories of your personal data: 

  * **Identification data:** including your name, telephone number, e-mail address, Customer ID Prescription, and similar information.
  * **Financial data:** including the details of your payment method such as a credit card, though we do not store the details of any card after the first order has been processed. 
  * **IT data:** including the pages you accessed; the date and time of your request and referral URL; the date and time at which you accessed them; your search queries within the site; and information about the device you used such as its hardware model, operation system version, unique device identifier, Internet protocol address, hardware settings, browser type, and browser language.

We only use your personal data within the limits authorized by current laws and regulations. Sometimes, we shall use your personal data because the laws and regulations actively require us to do so. In any case, we do not make any automated decisions solely on automatic processing which may produce legal effects concerning you, or similarly significantly affect you.

We use your personal data for the following purposes: 

  * We use your **identification data** in order to provide you with services as per our contractual obligations.
  * We use your **financial data** to process sales, returns, or replacement orders.
  * We use your **IT data** to track various analytics attributes so that we can continue to provide a more efficient service.

You can see the time limits for personal data storage below:

  * **Identification data** \- 7 years
  * **Financial data** \- 10 years
  * **IT data** \- 7 years

We inform you that we may share your personal data with companies outside of Clearly.

  * **Identification data** \- Yes. Limited strictly to SMS (name and telephone no)
  * **Financial data** \- No
  * **IT data** \- Yes

For recipients located in Canada/ US, there is no adequacy decision by the European Commission for such country; this means that the level of data protection in such country is not comparable with the level of data protection in the European Union. Therefore, we use as an appropriate safeguard to secure your personal data. You can request a copy hereof from privacy@coastal.com.

We have measures in place to protect your personal data against unauthorized access, use, or disclosure, including without limitation:

  * We implement and maintain sophisticated technical measures to ensure that your personal data is recorded and processed in complete confidentiality and security.
  * We implement and maintain appropriate restrictions on access to your personal data, and monitoring of the access, use, and transfer of personal data.
  * All employees who have access to your personal data are required to enter into non-disclosure or similar agreements, which imposes obligations for them to comply with our data privacy and confidentiality requirements.
  * We require any business partners and third party service providers with whom we may share your personal data to comply with any applicable data privacy and confidentiality requirements.
  * We provide data privacy training on a regular basis to our employees and third parties who have access to personal data.

Under applicable data protection laws and regulations, you have the following rights:

  * Of access to, rectification of, and/or erasure of your personal data.
  * To restrict or object to its processing.
  * To tell us that you do not wish to receive marketing information;
  * In some circumstances, to require certain of your personal data to be transferred to you or a third party.
  * To the extent our processing of your personal data is based upon your consent, to withdraw your consent, without affecting the lawfulness of our processing based on your consent before its withdrawal.

If you do not feel satisfied following this interaction, you may also lodge a complaint about our processing of your Personal Data with a Data Protection Authority. 

We will send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we may send you an email. Generally, you may not opt out of these communications, particularly as they are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to deactivate your account.

If you wish to subscribe to our email newsletter(s), we will use your name and email address to send the emails to you. Out of respect for your privacy, we provide you an option to unsubscribe. Please see the Opt Out section below.

We provide you the opportunity to opt out of having your personal information used for certain purposes, when we ask for this information. For example, if you purchase a product/service but do not wish to receive any addtional promotional emails from us, you may opt out at any time by following the unsubscribe link located at the bottom of each email communication. 

If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications, you may opt out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter.

By accepting these terms and conditions, you (i) allow us to share your data strictly with companies within Clearly/Coastal and (ii) give your express, specific and informed consent to receive emails of promotional materials concerning optical products and glasses from these companies. Your data will not be shared with any third party company. Each email sent to you by Clearly/Coastal and/or other companies within our group will include an 'unsubscribe' link.

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. 

**Option A**

Go to the [NAI website](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/). Their site will scan your computer/device for any 3rd party display or advertisements. A list of any 3rd party ads will then be populated and from there you can select the checkboxes next to the ads that you would like to remove. This ensures that advertisements will not come back to your computer/device as it is not registered to receive them. Note, the NAI website is not associated with Coastal Contacts Inc.

**Option B**

Manually access the cache and cookies of your browser and clear them. You will need to clear all to remove all 3rd party display advertisements.

[

We regularly review our compliance with our Privacy Notice, in particular to make it compliant with new laws and regulations regarding data protection. But, even if this Privacy Notice may change from time to time, we will not reduce your rights under this Privacy Notice without your explicit consent.

](https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies)
